league.org.uk 2016-04-30

# Privacy Policy - League Against Cruel Sports

### Privacy Policy

We (the League Against Cruel Sports) have created this Policy in order to demonstrate our commitment to preserving your privacy and safeguarding any personal details you provide to us via our website or by other means.  This Policy explains how we collect and use your information. 

By using our website or providing us with your personal information you are agreeing to this Policy. We may update this Policy at any time without notice to you, so please check it regularly.

**1.  When will I need to provide my details?**

We may collect personal information (for example your name, your address, your e-mail address, or your telephone number) from you when you:  
(a) Make a donation to us,  
(b) Register your Support;   
(c) Become a member;   
(d) Sign-up to our “Take Action” campaigns;  
(e) Respond to our mailings, raffles and competitions;    
(f) Make a purchase from our online shop;  
(g) Volunteer for us; or  
(h) Contact us or become involved with us in another way.

We may also collect information from the public domain, either directly or from third parties.  Except where permitted by law, we will never collect sensitive personal data about you without your consent. 

**2.  Why do you need my details and how do you use them?**

There are different reasons why we might need your personal details – the main ones are to process your donation, to process your application become a member and to send you information or provide goods and services that you have requested from us. 

We may also use your details to get in contact with you by post, telephone or e-mail, to keep you up to date on the work we do and the ways in which you can get involved and help us in our efforts to raise vital funds. 

We also use IP addresses to help us analyse trends, administer the site, track users’ movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information.

When dealing with your personal information we will at all times comply with the Data Protection Act 1998 (“the Act”), and any other applicable legislation.

**3.  Do you pass my details to any other organisations or individuals?**

We will never sell or share your personal data with other organisations. 

We may allow our staff, consultants, or other providers acting on our behalf to access and use your personal information for the purposes which you have provided it to us.  If we do this, we will not give those individuals/organisations any rights to use your personal information (or to contact you) except in accordance with our instructions and in accordance with this Policy. 

We may share or disclose your personal information if we are required to do so by any law or court order. 

**4.  How do you keep my information secure?**

This site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. 

All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers. Any payment transactions will be encrypted. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone.

We may send communications to you by email.  E-mail is not a fully secure means of communication, and whilst we try to keep our systems and communications protected we cannot guarantee this.

We make no representations about any other websites, and when you access any other website through a link on our website (including social media sites) you understand that it is independent from us and that we have no control over that website or the way your personal information is collected through those websites. Those websites may have their own privacy policies and we encourage you to look at those policies or contact the website operators directly to understand how your personal information is used.

**5.  Where is my information stored?**

The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored in the United States, a destination outside the European Economic Area ("EEA"). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.

**6.  How do you use cookies on this website?**  
For information on how cookies are used on this website, please see our Cookie Policy.

**7.  What if I don’t want you to use my details anymore?**  
If you have provided us with your details, but decide at a later date that you no longer want to receive information from us, or if you wish to update us that your contact details have changed, simply let us know by: 

  * Sending an email to [info@league.org.uk](mailto:info@league.org.uk)
  * Writing to the following postal address: League Against Cruel Sports, New Sparling House, Holloway Hill, Godalming, Surrey GU7 1QZ
  * Calling the following telephone number: 01483 524 250

Instructions for unsubscribing from e-mails will also be included in each e-mail communication we send.  
If you have any questions, comments, or concerns about this Policy, please contact us at [info@league.org.uk](mailto:info@league.org.uk)  

## Donate to save animals

£10  
£20  
£30 Other Monthly  
Single
